<Presentation PresentationClass="profile">
  <PageOptions Columns="2"/>
  <WindowName>New Features</WindowName>  
  <PageTitle>New Features</PageTitle>
  <PageBackLinkName></PageBackLinkName>
  <PageBackLinkURL></PageBackLinkURL>
  <PageSubTitle></PageSubTitle>
  <PageDescription></PageDescription>  
  <PanelList>
    <Panel type="header"  />
    <Panel type="page" />
    <Panel Type="active">
      <Module ID="MiniSearch"  />
      <Module ID="MainMenu"  />      
    </Panel>
    <Panel Type="main">
      <Module ID="HTMLBlock">
        <ParamList>
          <Param Name="HTML">

<style type="text/css">
#suckerfishmenu li#about a { background-color: #6A7D7D !important; }
ul li { padding-top: 10px; }
#new-features { display: none; }
</style>

<p>The new and improved UCSF Profiles offers a variety of features that make it an even more effective research networking and collaboration tool. Find out what's new and please <a href="mailto:profiles@ucsf.edu?Subject=New%20Features%20Feedback">share any comments</a>.</p>

<div style="border: 1px solid #CCC; padding:5px 15px; margin-bottom: 10px;">
<h2 style="color: #CA7C29;font-size: 16px;">Highlights</h2>
<ul class="highlights"> 
  <li><strong>Search by topic for all recent UCSF papers</strong> with automated help in pinpointing
      specific concepts (e.g. all recent papers from UCSF on Post-Traumatic Epilepsies)
  </li>
  <li><strong>Add customized keywords</strong> to reflect your personal interests (e.g. comparative 
      effectiveness research, digital health, mentoring) – 
      <span style="color:#990000;font-style:italic;">Top User Request!</span>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Get a personalized URL</strong> for your profile page
      (e.g. profiles.ucsf.edu/jane.smith)
  </li>
  <li><strong>View the time course of an individual's publishing and collaborations</strong> 
      (e.g. assess whether someone is an expert because of a classic paper written a decade ago 
      or because of recent contributions)
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 style="font-size: 14px;padding-left:38px">And there’s more. See other new features and details below.</h3>
</div>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Videos</strong><br />
      You can now enhance your profile page with YouTube and UCTV videos. In the Featured Videos
      section, simply enter the title and web address for your YouTube and/or UCTV video. Videos 
      will appear on your profile page within several minutes.<br />
      <img src="images/video.jpg" alt="Video" style="padding:10px 0 0 89px;width:506px;" />
  </li>
  <li><strong>New Search Options</strong><br />
      UCSF Profiles now allows you to search by a keyword or concept and return not only the 
      list of experts at UCSF (6000+) but also all recent papers from UCSF on a topic.<br />
      <img src="images/conceptsearch.jpg" alt="Search Options" style="padding:10px 0 0 90px" />
  </li>
  <li><strong>Highlight Your Interests</strong><br />
      The feature most requested by profile owners over the last 2 years has been the option to 
      add customized keywords that reflect personal interests. Now you can! Your customized and searchable 
      keywords complement the existing automatically generated concepts derived from publications.     
  </li>
  <li><strong>Personalized URLs</strong><br />
      It's now easy to remember your profile page web address, and to share it on business cards,
      email signatures, etc. Your new USCF Profiles address is based on your first and last name (e.g.
      profiles.ucsf.edu/john.smith). Find your customized address in the browser address bar when you 
      visit your profile.    
  </li>
  <li><strong>New Visualizations of Helpful Information </strong>
     <ul>
        <li><strong>View the time course of publishing and collaborations </strong>
            (e.g. assess whether someone is an expert because of a classic paper written a decade ago
            or because of recent contributions; identify recent versus long-past co-authors). Each 
            individual's publishing timeline appears above the list of relevant publications. <br />
            <img src="images/pubsgraph.jpg" alt="Publication timeline" style="padding:10px 0 0 45px" />
        </li>
        <li><strong>Explore Networks Associated with an Expert</strong> (right column on each profile) 
            <ul> 
               <li><strong>Related Concepts</strong> includes subject areas related to an individual's 
                   publishing history. Select "See all" to view different visualizations, including a 
                   timeline that demonstrates topics an individual has published on over time. <br />  
                   <img src="images/timeline.jpg" alt="Expertise timeline" style="padding:10px 0 0 0" />
               </li>   
               <li><strong>Related Co-Authors</strong> includes subject areas related to an individual's
                   publishing history. Select "See all" to view visualizations including number of 
                   co-publications by individual, a map of co-author publications, etc.   <br />  
                   <img src="images/detailstab.jpg" alt="Related Co-Authors" style="padding:10px 0 0 0" />
               </li>   
            </ul>    
        </li>      
     </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Updated Look and Feel</strong><br />
      You'll notice some subtle but helpful changes, including a new table of contents that make it
      easy to quickly review individual profiles.<br />
      <img src="images/toc.jpg" alt="Look and Feel" style="padding:10px 0 0 80px" />
  </li>
</ul>
<p><br />Do you have questions or ideas for new UCSF Profiles features? Let us know at <a href="mailo:profiles@ucsf.edu">profiles@ucsf.edu</a>. </p>
        
          </Param>
        </ParamList>
      </Module>
      <Panel Type="passive"/>
      <Panel type="footer" />
    </Panel> 
  </PanelList>
</Presentation>

